[{"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888e", "question": "What is Dennis the Menace's last name?", "answer": "Mitchell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca0c", "question": "What is the name of the largest moon of Jupiter?", "answer": "Ganymede", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b8", "question": "\"Video Killed the Radio Star\" was the debut music video on which channel in 1981?", "answer": "MTV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5a", "question": "What was the first ever animated film to be nominated for the Best Picture Oscar?", "answer": "Beauty and the Beast", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4afd49076251badbeabf", "question": "What was the first food to be intentionally microwaved?", "answer": "Popcorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59774274284458f1d7854420", "question": "What was the second major television series starring Andy Griffith", "answer": "Matlock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a955e61d1b4d384d5d679", "question": "Which fruit is affected by a grey type of fungus known commonly as Noble Rot?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c3e9952ebfabb9c85d8a971", "question": "Eirene was the Greek goddess of what?", "answer": "Peace", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a555", "question": "What city is the capital of the US state of South Dakota?", "answer": "Pierre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb22065ff7d326b622a71", "question": "What is the name given to the dish of dates, or prunes, wrapped in bacon?", "answer": "Devils on Horseback", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb8", "question": "What was the colorful nickname of elderly frat member Joseph Pulasky in the 2003 film \"Old School\"?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd1", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"schmaltz\"?", "answer": "Yiddish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c04d", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Belgium?", "answer": "Common kestrel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b535", "question": "How many pawns does each player have at the start of a chess game?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd7947e83c707845b2173", "question": "What popular movie musical, directed by John Huston, was released in 1982?", "answer": "\"Annie\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee3", "question": "By what professional name is comic book writer Stanley Martin Leiber better known?", "answer": "Stan Lee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4c8e49076251badbead7", "question": "What was the name of the space capsule that carried the first woman in space?", "answer": "Vostok 6 -- It carried Soviet cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova in space on 1963.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e33", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Down the Rabbit-Hole\"?", "answer": "Alice in Wonderland", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe73df7eec85e375820b26f", "question": "How many countries border on the Alps?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b3e101dd7bf43be5e7b7", "question": "What city created a new beachfront when it hosted the Olympics?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3c", "question": "Which element appears eighth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b33c", "question": "What is the name of Agrippa's husband, who she poisoned?", "answer": "Claudius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c734", "question": "Despite its name, what species of whale is most likely to die in mass strandings on the beach?", "answer": "Pilot whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ee", "question": "Leukophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "The color white", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59c1cdb87bd84c0ea43ad42d", "question": "Which country borders Macedonia to the north?", "answer": "Serbia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad34", "question": "Which company developed the A6M fighter plane known as \"Zero\" during WWII?", "answer": "Mitsubishi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008a56cf842fa4c4ba968f", "question": "What nationality was Johnny Weissmuller?", "answer": "Hungarian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8df", "question": "What describes a person with no skin pigment?", "answer": "An Albino", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ca3dbb44f0f6af5b06663e", "question": "What is the capital of Andorra?", "answer": "Andorra la Vella", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afde", "question": "The gun battle at the O.K. Corral was fought between the Earp Brothers and what gang?", "answer": "Clanton Gang", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f8c601dd7bf43be5e848", "question": "Who said, \"I don't make jokes. I just watch the government and report the facts\"?", "answer": "Will Rogers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c23b", "question": "Which European city is served by Galileo Galilei Airport?", "answer": "Pisa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76d", "question": "What lake in Oregon was created about 7,000 years ago by the eruption of Mount Mazama?", "answer": "Crater Lake", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931b", "question": "In the 2002 movie \"Spiderman\", what was Peter Parker's profession?", "answer": "Photographer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339826", "question": "What were Laurel and Hardy's first names?", "answer": "Stan and Oliver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe25938658e585fda9cfa41", "question": "What shape is \"chiocciole\" pasta?", "answer": "Snail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cd75ae347d002c297e4c2", "question": "What is the only continent without native reptiles and snakes?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf9", "question": "What year did Edward Jenner introduce the world's first successful vaccine?", "answer": "1796", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0c", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"Road Warrior\"?", "answer": "Mad Max", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b235", "question": "After his trial, Michael Jackson fled Neverland Ranch for what island nation?", "answer": "Bahrain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae60", "question": "What do the 36 columns surrounding the Lincoln Memorial represent?", "answer": "The number of states at the time of Lincoln's death", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e0", "question": "What type of creature is a copperhead?", "answer": "A snake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0c", "question": "What year did Wayne Gretzky's professional hockey career start?", "answer": "1978", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c45e", "question": "What is mixed with clay, baked in a kiln, and then pulverized in order to make Portland cement?", "answer": "Limestone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a640", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Badger State\"?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec6", "question": "What's the subject of the 1969 memoir \"Thirteen Days\"?", "answer": "The Cuban Missile Crisis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a45c", "question": "Grenada is part of which continent?", "answer": "North America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa3b", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 501?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e9", "question": "How old was writer Arthur C. Clarke when he passed away in 2008?", "answer": "90", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "595643fe803c1f1ebcc4a032", "question": "Ketchup was sold in the 1830\u2019s as what?", "answer": "Medicine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfee", "question": "Mary Read and Anne Bonny had what job in common?", "answer": "Pirates", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ce", "question": "What sport is the Heisman Trophy awarded in?", "answer": "American college football", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92f", "question": "What yard line must a football team drive to, to reach the \"red zone\"?", "answer": "The 20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c511", "question": "What are deheaded, deveined and sorted by size in a Laitram machine?", "answer": "Shrimp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb9", "question": "Which Philosopher said \"Hell is other people\"?", "answer": "Jean Paul Sartre", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac1", "question": "The book \"The Second Sex\" was written by who?", "answer": "Simone de Beauvoir", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ff", "question": "In the 1890's, what type of cheese did a California man named David Jacks introduce?", "answer": "Monterey Jack", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba29", "question": "What was the original name of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "Liberty Enlightening the World", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a76", "question": "What was the name of the lead character in the novel \"The Scarlet Letter\"?", "answer": "Hester Prynne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067fbfff9c0647b50a8087", "question": "Overall, how many medals did US swimmer Michael Phelps win at the 2016 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "6", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c13c", "question": "With which instrument is jazz musician Charlie Mingus principally associated?", "answer": "Double Bass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e3", "question": "What letter in the alphabet is the only one with more than one syllable?", "answer": "W", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c635", "question": "Earth's seasonal changes are caused by what?", "answer": "Earth's axial tilt as it orbits the Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b274", "question": "What army occupied Addis Ababa in May 1936?", "answer": "Italy's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9b", "question": "What is the capital of the Republic of Nauru?", "answer": "Yaren", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b069", "question": "What company introduced the first canned ham in the US in 1926?", "answer": "Hormel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9bbc5364247bf200fb8a7", "question": "Lusaka is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a65c", "question": "The port city of Sandusky is located in which state?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc57", "question": "What is the literal translation of the dish \"Pad Thai\"?", "answer": "Fried Thai style", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a70d6c0f9723ab15cb5a", "question": "What is the crescent-shaped part of a fingernail called?", "answer": "Lunula", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae02", "question": "Who was the first human in outer space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ce", "question": "In the movie \"Four Weddings and a Funeral\", which character dies?", "answer": "Gareth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067c80ff9c0647b50a806c", "question": "How old was David Bowie at the time of his death in 2016?", "answer": "69", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fcdca4edfd43a087adc3", "question": "What number is represented by \"V\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "5", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6aa3420565ad31a57c812", "question": "Who was President Gerald Ford's vice president?", "answer": "Nelson Rockefeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133937d", "question": "In the movie \"Interview with the Vampire\", who cut Lestat's throat?", "answer": "Claudia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe36dab0ada16518afdc043", "question": "Who was the founder and head designer of Ecko clothing?", "answer": "Marc Ecko", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391cf", "question": "Who directed the 2007 sci-fi movie \"Sunshine\"?", "answer": "Danny Boyle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b94f", "question": "What sport did hall-of-famer Mickey Mantle play?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e2", "question": "A pike most resembles what kind of weapon?", "answer": "Spear", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8c", "question": "How much does it cost to purchase Boardwalk in the standard game of Monopoly?", "answer": "$400", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff20e7f31a458464a93c424", "question": "Peter Quill's ship in \"Guardians of the Galaxy\" was named for what actor?", "answer": "Alyssa Milano", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ccf7c7cb37b32637bdc44c9", "question": "What animal is an orb weaver?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339242", "question": "How many friends are featured on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Six", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b8", "question": "Which British rock group released a debut album called \"Parachutes\"?", "answer": "Coldplay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3d", "question": "What singer's autobiography was titled \"Man in Black\"?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a8", "question": "Whose California grave marker reads \"1935 - 1998 And the Beat Goes On?\"", "answer": "Sonny Bono's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24d", "question": "What year did Huey Lewis and the News record the song \"Jacob's Ladder\"?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff214f631a458464a93c45a", "question": "What is the name of the US President's official guest house?", "answer": "Blair House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339850", "question": "How many legs does the catbus have in \"My Neighbour Totoro\"?", "answer": "12", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339511", "question": "Which sci-fi movie starred Jane Fonda as \"Queen of the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "Barbarella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb61365dad637d903c882e", "question": "What is the smallest country in South America?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067a13ff9c0647b50a8053", "question": "What is the United Kingdom European Union membership referendum of 2016, more widely known as?", "answer": "Brexit", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0bb", "question": "Mace is the outer covering of which common spice?", "answer": "Nutmeg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133997f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Krusty the Clown's helper monkey?", "answer": "Mr. Teeny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acec", "question": "What Canadian city boasts the world's richest rodeo that was first staged in 1912?", "answer": "Calgary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be72", "question": "What is the Darlington Raceway also known as?", "answer": "The Track Too Tough to Tame", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe937cb6bd93ce3a4e5f677", "question": "Genuphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Knees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a223", "question": "Who sang the song \"I'll Be Missing You\" in 1997?", "answer": "Puff Daddy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7f", "question": "In 1995, who became the first Asian player to be named Rookie of the Year in Major League Baseball?", "answer": "Hideo Nomo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e4d", "question": "What eccentric artist based his famous moustache on that worn by painter Diego Velazquez?", "answer": "Salvador Dali", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c091", "question": "What are scaup?", "answer": "Ducks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ac", "question": "Which actress got her start at age 13 playing the 12-year old prostitute Iris in a 1976 thriller?", "answer": "Jodie Foster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d04", "question": "What author's books include \"Call of the Wild\" and \"White Fang\"?", "answer": "Jack London", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae89", "question": "What military alliance did the US join in 1949?", "answer": "NATO", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b12b", "question": "What was the name of the uprising that took place in Kenya between 1952 and 1960?", "answer": "Mau Mau Uprising", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d17", "question": "What year was Beethoven born in?", "answer": "1770", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c0", "question": "In pool, what color is the 6-ball?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afc5", "question": "Which US president signed the Emancipation Proclamation?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6a0a06c0f9723ab15cb36", "question": "What was the inspiration behind a 12-person jury?", "answer": "The 12 Apostles of Jesus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a71", "question": "What is the name of the girl Bruce Springsteen is singing to in the song \"Born to Run\"?", "answer": "Wendy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8bf", "question": "What three-mile-wide New Brunswick island was FDR's summer home?", "answer": "Campobello", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30a", "question": "What character did Natascha McElhone play on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Karen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc10d6ce05a3942286f0d", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Private Eyes\"?", "answer": "Hall and Oates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c78ffbde8045e48466c4", "question": "What is the only mammal native to Iceland?", "answer": "Artic fox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601214f563c99d48cd169ae4", "question": "Which researcher corrected Einstein's theory of a static universe?", "answer": "Edwin Hubble -- He concluded that the universe is actually expanding, something Einstein would admit was his own blunder.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bbd50ca00d154d7af00b8d8", "question": "Scott Raynor is the original drummer of which rock band?", "answer": "Blink-182", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891f", "question": "What is the name of the dragon in \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "Smaug", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6bd46fb6c85e9e634ff65", "question": "What element has the periodic table name Sb?", "answer": "Antimony", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b3a", "question": "In the John Cougar song \"Jack & Diane\", what are they eating outside the Tastee-Freez?", "answer": "A chili dog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b59", "question": "In Greek mythology, how many labours were imposed on Hercules?", "answer": "12", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ec", "question": "What is the technical name of the pound sign?", "answer": "Octothorpe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60121b0b63c99d48cd169b0a", "question": "The word \"susurrus\" is an example of which literary device?", "answer": "Onomatopoeia -- Some words sound just like their meanings.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e9800ebfabb9c85d8a968", "question": "On the TV Show \"Night Court\", what was Bull's IQ?", "answer": "181", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51ca6ff04d658268c9319", "question": "Which U.S. aircraft carrier was sunk at the Battle of Midway?", "answer": "USS Yorktown CV-5", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974b", "question": "What pop star originally began her career as Christian singer \"Katherine Hudson\"?", "answer": "Katy Perry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339594", "question": "What type of wine does Miles refuse to drink in the movie \"Sideways\"?", "answer": "Merlot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbc", "question": "What addiction-inducing crop did Christopher Columbus discover in Cuba in 1492?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c528", "question": "How long does it take a human blood cell to make a complete circuit of the human body?", "answer": "One minute", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339002", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Barnaby Rudge\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8ab4d01dd7bf43be5e767", "question": "What part of the computer does \"QWERTY\" refer to?", "answer": "The keyboard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c209", "question": "Which country were the 1912 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590087395304ceedb84e8994", "question": "What drink began in Morison's drug store in Waco, Texas in 1885?", "answer": "Dr. Pepper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a4", "question": "Which country were the 1928 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81b39d0de9af39e9d4676", "question": "What ancient people created massive head figurines out of boulders?", "answer": "The Olmec", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e10", "question": "What British comedian refers to himself as an \"executive transvestite\"?", "answer": "Eddie Izzard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133968a", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", where do Patty and Selma live?", "answer": "Spinster City Apartments", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5902a166cad1ec93f27df776", "question": "What dialect term describes rough cider made from unselected apples?", "answer": "Scrumpy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb40365ff7d326b622a83", "question": "What year was Budweiser first introduced?", "answer": "1876", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b271", "question": "What did \"Glamorous Glennis\" do on October 19, 1947?", "answer": "Broke the sound barrier for the first time", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e97cfebfabb9c85d8a966", "question": "What TV show has the character Michael Stivic?", "answer": "All in the Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe938a76bd93ce3a4e5f687", "question": "What is the standard unit of kinetic energy?", "answer": "Joule", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e94d1fc5ea27d7a1303aed6", "question": "In what US state is the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c432", "question": "How many pairs of ribs are there in the average human skeleton?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5eb739095e259d7869087330", "question": "Which organ has 4 chambers?", "answer": "Heart", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b46801dd7bf43be5e7bf", "question": "What Marvel superhero was created to sell orange juice?", "answer": "Captain Citrus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a9", "question": "What year was author J. D. Salinger born?", "answer": "1919", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb1137e83c707845b210b", "question": "Which planet was discovered by mathematical prediction before it was directly observed?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe655aaae7e414034b5aeb7", "question": "Which ancient wonder was burned down by a fame-seeking arsonist?", "answer": "Temple of Artemis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c009", "question": "In pool, what color is the eight ball?", "answer": "Black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c6510775fa611bce67d1", "question": "What short-lived product did Pepsi introduce in 1992?", "answer": "Crystal Pepsi -- Marketed during the 1993 Superbowl with an ad featuring Van Halen, it did well at first. It later fizzled.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7fe5ff048f679a45ac16", "question": "What is the most dense stable element?", "answer": "Osmium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adaa", "question": "The \"Indus Valley Civilization\" is also known by what other name?", "answer": "Harappan Civilization", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b7c3e662d71a53651017", "question": "What is the occupation of \"Fahrenheit 451\" protagonist Guy Montag?", "answer": "Fireman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5cb", "question": "Before being sold, to which country did the web suffix \".me\" belong to?", "answer": "Montenegro", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d1185a4fea7fe947a22284", "question": "By what name is Lignite often referred to as?", "answer": "Brown coal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea3", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Alexander and Cookie?", "answer": "Blondie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae8c", "question": "When did Arizona and New Mexico become states?", "answer": "1912", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ca", "question": "What year did Jean Anouilh write the play \"The Lark\"?", "answer": "1952", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5971e08489261e916c8e09ac", "question": "What US state was \"Steak 'n Shake\" founded in?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff51a8aff04d658268c9306", "question": "Odysseus left home to fight in what war?", "answer": "Trojan War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a019", "question": "What actor was the narrator in the movie \"The Right Stuff\"?", "answer": "Levon Helm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a464", "question": "Mount Rushmore is located near which town in South Dakota?", "answer": "Keystone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b1", "question": "In what non-Spanish-speaking city would you find the Spanish Steps?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c872", "question": "What piece of technology did IBM develop in 1973 that they nicknamed Winchester?", "answer": "A disk drive", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed3", "question": "What jazzman's first recording band was the Hot Five?", "answer": "Louis Armstrong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391cb", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Aliens\"?", "answer": "James Cameron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a10", "question": "What year was the setting for the movie \"Animal House\"?", "answer": "1962", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c66d877e98cb977789b8", "question": "What is the last remaining French territory in North America?", "answer": "Saint-Pierre and Miquelon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e8a67c89a45431f553a9cd2", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56e", "question": "Is Salton Sea fresh water or salt water?", "answer": "Salt water", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea4531ff048f679a45ab91", "question": "What type of muscle bends a joint in the body?", "answer": "Flexor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbdf", "question": "What is the last name of the founder of the Papa John's pizza chain?", "answer": "Schnatter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ef", "question": "Of the six main cast members on the TV show \u201cFriends\u201d, which was the oldest?", "answer": "Lisa Kudrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c97f", "question": "What constellation is represented by scales?", "answer": "Libra", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c908", "question": "What are the Chiuhauhan, Nubian, and Alaskan?", "answer": "Deserts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e0", "question": "What term is given to the scientific study of all aspects of the life of fungi?", "answer": "Mycology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a7bb20565ad31a57c7ed", "question": "What phrase did British Admiral Horatio Nelson coin thanks to a battle injury?", "answer": "Turn a blind eye", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65c401f3c0ead6880d610", "question": "In the Bible, who was the coppersmith that did Paul much evil?", "answer": "Alexander", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d1", "question": "What year did tennis player Martina Navratilova turn pro?", "answer": "1975", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb1c0aff497e33de805791d", "question": "What three teams did Babe Ruth play for?", "answer": "Boston Red Sox, New York Yankees, Boston Braves", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dcc", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"ombudsman\"?", "answer": "Swedish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ae94f4574a5ce6b56b824d", "question": "Which African country is Lilongwe the capital of?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdd5ff70499cffc60b84237", "question": "Apart from the toga, what was the main article of Roman fashion?", "answer": "Tunic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601601b0fe83fe1f2a824c61", "question": "Many countries do not forthrightly recognize May Day but celebrate which other holiday in its stead?", "answer": "International Workers Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339828", "question": "What legendary funk band was formed by George Clinton?", "answer": "Parliament", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc32dec223966ae8f887b", "question": "What singer staged a comeback with \"The Emancipation of Mimi,\" the second-best-selling album worldwide in 2005?", "answer": "Mariah Carey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81e", "question": "What kind of cool star will our Sun become in approximately 5 billion years?", "answer": "A red giant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e86006d333868d34d747", "question": "Who was the top Australian flying ace in World War I?", "answer": "Robert Little", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa84", "question": "What is the capital of Djibouti?", "answer": "Djibouti City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f9", "question": "What year did James Garfield start his presidency?", "answer": "1881", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a568", "question": "The city of Pittsburgh is located in which state?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008d9b9f4f3bc4a292f8611", "question": "When did the Mayflower reach America?", "answer": "The Mayflower landed along the shores of Cape Cod on November 11, 1620.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03d", "question": "Sociophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Society and social situations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ae", "question": "Who signed off his radio show by saying \"Keep your feet on the ground and keep reaching for the stars\"?", "answer": "Casey Kasem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ce", "question": "Where was Enrico Caruso born?", "answer": "Naples, Italy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58bb34fee368446ca7bd684d", "question": "Which modern-day country is often considered as the birthplace of coffee?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a329", "question": "Who played the role of Elaine in the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Annette O'Toole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bff", "question": "What movie does the line \"Nobody puts Baby in the corner\" hails form?", "answer": "Dirty Dancing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e3", "question": "Who is the author of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" novel series?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b830", "question": "What is the device that measures the number of steps you take when walking or running?", "answer": "Pedometer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339604", "question": "What nickname does Marshall Samuel Gerard go by in the 1993 movie \"The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Big Dog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d37", "question": "What popular comic book character was created by Jerry Siegel and Joe Shuster?", "answer": "Superman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bbc954160f0007efaba0e61", "question": "What is entamaphobia?", "answer": "Fear of doors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0b", "question": "Who won a Pulitzer Prize for his novel \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339421", "question": "What was the name of the doorman at Rick's in the movie \"Casablanca\"?", "answer": "Abdul", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a8d790aac110e4167092", "question": "If you order a Snakebite cocktail in the UK, what would you get?", "answer": "A mix of lager and cider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989aa75cb8751d53e7d7604", "question": "What name is given to the area of the sky that is obscured by the Milky Way?", "answer": "The Zone of Avoidance", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9de", "question": "Which continent is the natural habitat of the Ostrich?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c505", "question": "What is a group of apes called?", "answer": "A shrewdness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9bb", "question": "What is the name of an eagle's nest?", "answer": "An Eyrie", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a61b", "question": "What US city is located near Lackland Air Force Base?", "answer": "San Antonio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddf", "question": "What kind of wine accompanies Hannibal Lecter's liver and fava bean dinner?", "answer": "Chianti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339967", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what actor is the voice of Comic Book Guy?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071e5d3745b36be73039e2", "question": "Which comic book publisher publishes the \"Revival\" series?", "answer": "Image Comics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1a5", "question": "Which sport awards the Sam Maguire Cup?", "answer": "Gaelic Football", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e5", "question": "What sport has its name abbreviated to BMX?", "answer": "Bicycle Moto-cross", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be73", "question": "What is LP Field also known as?", "answer": "The Woodshed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb89", "question": "How many dice are used in a game of Yahtzee?", "answer": "Five", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bac", "question": "What band's first Top 10 hit in the US was 1984's \"Legs\"?", "answer": "ZZ Top", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc1", "question": "Where do fallen Norse warriors go?", "answer": "Valhalla", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af11", "question": "What \"trail\" did thousands of pioneers follow to Oregon during the 1800s?", "answer": "Oregon Trail", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4bff49076251badbeacb", "question": "Which U.S. President had the most children?", "answer": "John Tyler -- The 10th president had 16 children \u2014 15 with his two wives and one born out of wedlock.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a11a", "question": "What is the real identity of Aquaman?", "answer": "Arthur Curry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9df61e748bb36357acde8", "question": "The City of Hot Coffee is in what US state?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff516dcff04d658268c92f6", "question": "Which organ was typically left in the body of mummies?", "answer": "Heart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6ba50fb6c85e9e634ff50", "question": "Who composed \"Invitation to the Dance\" in 1819?", "answer": "Carl Maria von Weber", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f6ec7a9e54d890926f6ca", "question": "What city is home to the tallest skyscraper in the world?", "answer": "Dubai, UAE -- The Burj Khalifa soars over Dubai at a height of 2,717 ft.  It has 163 floors with a hotel, residences and offices.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938a", "question": "How many Oscars did the 2001 movie \"A Beautiful Mind\" win?", "answer": "Four", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0e386fcbed638185eaa22", "question": "What U.S. state is nicknamed \"The Sooner State\"?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391aa", "question": "Who played James Bond in the 1971 film \"Diamonds Are Forever\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cb65877e98cb97778a19", "question": "Which Asian capital used to be called Peking?", "answer": "Beijing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a174", "question": "What was the name of the witch in the \"Emu's\" TV series?", "answer": "Grotbags", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b037", "question": "What Major League Baseball park was originally called Weeghman Park?", "answer": "Wrigley Field", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8aaae01dd7bf43be5e75e", "question": "If someone said \"you are olid\", what would they mean?", "answer": "You smell extremely unpleasant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d077e0870e6f05ba600868", "question": "Who directed the 1995 film \"Boys on the Side\"?", "answer": "Herbert Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d3", "question": "What former country was Martina Navratilova born in?", "answer": "Czechoslovakia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b48ae49076251badbeaa4", "question": "What space shuttle did John Glenn travel in when he returned to space?", "answer": "Discovery -- Glenn flew on\u00a0Space Shuttle\u00a0Discovery's\u00a0STS-95\u00a0mission in 1998.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab57", "question": "Which former Soviet Republic in Central Asia has Tashkent as its capital?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cd40e06685cf15b733e9896", "question": "In fencing what is the name of the action when two fencers make physical contact with any part of their bodies (or hilts)?", "answer": "Corps-a-corps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c314", "question": "What irrational mathematical constant is known as the golden ratio?", "answer": "1.6180339887", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bfe00fcb668d7dfe168b5c7", "question": "When did Napoleon Bonaparte begin his reign as Emperor of the French?", "answer": "1804", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c4cefbde8045e48466a2", "question": "How long is an African elephant's gestation period?", "answer": "22 months -- At birth, the calves can weigh about 250 pounds and drink up to three gallons of their mother's milk per day.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5f", "question": "Who played Will on the TV show \"Will & Grace\"?", "answer": "Eric McCormack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb28bdc9bff04efae6d753", "question": "What year was Mario Puzo's novel \"The Godfather\" published?", "answer": "1969", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943b", "question": "What brand of motorcycle does Tom Cruise ride in the 1986 movie \"Top Gun\"?", "answer": "Kawasaki", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad2a", "question": "In what year did the Black Monday event occur?", "answer": "1987", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feccd3aec223966ae8f88aa", "question": "What is the name of the event where tributes are chosen for \"The Hunger Games\"?", "answer": "The Reaping", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f56", "question": "In one myth, what dance was first performed by Hi'iaka to appease the volcano goddess, Pele?", "answer": "The hula", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b465", "question": "Who ordered Atlanta be burned in 1864?", "answer": "General Sherman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ff", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek goddess Aphrodite?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ec4d08d98002fdd633ba", "question": "Which character, that first appeared in the book \"Winnie-the-Pooh\", loves watercress?", "answer": "Roo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff3ce2a4f032c0db195b48c", "question": "When did the\u00a0fall of Constantinople occur?", "answer": "The fall of Constantinople followed a 53-day siege that had begun on 6 April 1453.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a899b9e60d398dc9cf7a69f", "question": "What element's atomic number is 74?", "answer": "Tungsten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062ce4c9d816e292245c2f", "question": "Actor James Franco once sold a sculpture made of what?", "answer": "In 2011, a collector paid $10,000 for a \"non-visible\" sculpture titled\u00a0\"Fresh Air\"\u00a0and billed as \"an endless tank of oxygen\".", "category": "arts"}]